http://www.usaswimming.org/landing-pages/privacy-policy

Club Portal
Online Meet Entry (OME)
Club Portal
Online Meet Entry (OME)
Privacy Policy
USA Swimming (“USA Swimming,” “us,” “we,” or “our”) is committed to protecting the privacy of its website users, swimmers, and families. We have prepared this privacy policy to describe our practices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of personal information. USA Swimming operates a general audience website as well as the SWIMS platform, and the privacy practices of both are discussed below. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make revisions that change the way we collect, use, or share personal information, we will post those changes in this Privacy Policy and will abide by the terms of the previous policy until we have your consent for the new policy. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically to keep up to date on our most current policies and practices. We note the effective date of the latest version of our Privacy Policy at the end of this Privacy Policy.
The WebsiteThe SWIMS platformThe DeckPass Plus Mobile App
What Information is Collected and How We Collect ItCookies and How We Use Them
SWIMS
Deck Pass Plus
How We Use The InformationThird Party Sites and Sponsors
SecurityCommunications
THE WEBSITE As an interactive website, we collect certain personal information, which is more fully outlined below.
THE SWIMS PLATFORM The SWIMS member management platform performs logistical and organizational tasks for USA Swimming, Local Swimming Committees (“LSC”), clubs, and athlete and non-athlete members. Some data in SWIMS is entered by USA Swimming staff,
while other data may be entered by third parties like an LSC, a local team, or a vendor or representative of a local team. In certain scenarios you may be able to enter information about yourself or others into the platform as well. Please review the
SWIMS Terms of Use for more information.
THE “DECK PASS PLUS” MOBILE APP The “Deck Pass Plus” mobile app allows for sharing and updating of times, rankings, patches, certifications, and images or results from USA Swimming events.
WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED AND HOW WE COLLECT IT We collect information when you, your team, a representative or vendor of your team, an LSC, or another party submits information to us. To enable visitors to participate in some of our activities, we may ask them to provide personal information including
name, e-mail address, telephone number and date of birth. Here are some of the ways we may collect personally identifying information from our visitors: During registrationsOnline surveysOnline purchasingForums registrationWeb server logsGathering device informationBiographical data that you submit to your teamTime information submitted by your team or a LSC
COOKIES AND HOW WE USE THEM“Cookies” are small bits of information that may be placed on the hard drive of a computer. Cookies are used to gather basic tracking information and to present advertisements and are placed on your hard drive by many major websites. They
are especially necessary when ordering a product online. Cookies allow websites to determine the type of computer operating system and browser that you and other viewers are using, which enables websites to improve access to content. We do not link the information collected through cookies to personally identifiable information provided by users participating in our activities.
SWIMS We collect information for the SWIMS member management platform when you voluntarily submit it to us, but also when your information is submitted on your behalf by a third party. The SWIMS platform may collect information such as a name, birth date, address,
email, ethnicity, disabilities, gender, club affiliation, results, awards, and honors. Some of the ways information is collected for the SWIMS platform include: Submission of data by your team, LSCs, or other third partiesRegistration of a team or swimmer on the platformUser submission
DECK PASS PLUSWe collect information for the Deck Pass Plus application when you or others submit it through the application. The Deck Pass Plus application may collect information such as your name, results and rankings, certifications, digital patches, and images or video recordings of you. It will also collect any information which you choose to post publicly.
HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION Information we collect may be used for record and score keeping, internal marketing purposes, to help us determine how to fix or improve our site, monitor usage, customize content, facilitate transactions, and contact you for verification purposes.
We do not sell, distribute, trade or otherwise transfer personally identifiable information obtained from a user to any third party, either within our own organization or outside it, unless the user has provided his or her consent.
HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION We may share information with service providers that perform services for USA Swimming such as hosting, marketing assistance, and website optimization. There may also be instances where we may disclose information without providing you a choice such as
to protect our legal rights or those of affiliated companies, employees, or agents, to protect the safety and security of other users, for risk management purposes, or to comply with the law. California residents may be entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information (if any) we share with third parties or affiliates for direct marketing.
THIRD-PARTY SITES AND SPONSORS Our site contains links to other sites whose information practices may be different from ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices, which may differ from ours. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of any third party website
or applications before transmitting information to such third party.
SECURITYWe employ reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect personal information. While there is no such thing as “perfect security” on the Internet, we will take reasonable steps to ensure the safety of personal information. In the event that we are required to contact you regarding the security of your data, we may do so by email, mail, or telephone as permitted by law.
COMMUNICATIONS Questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or any other privacy or security issue, please contact us. info@usaswimming.org
Copyright 2020 USA Swimming. All Rights Reserved.
Privacy Policy
Terms & Conditions
